American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIg. 1887-1891 APS.Archives.IIg APS.Archives.IIg
American Philosophical Society
American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIg
1887-1891
APS.Archives.IIg
American Philosophical Society
1.0 section
This is part of the large inventory for the American Philosophical Society Archives. For complete information concerning this collection, please view the Collection Description.
American Philosophical Society.
- Papers
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 5, 1887; 11x8; Georgia Historical Society
    Scope and Contents note
    Savannah, A.L.S.: W[illia]m Harden,librarian. 1p. Concerning Society's publication. Refers to Eli Geddings.
  - Letter to secretaries of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], Jan. 6, 1887; 9-1/2x6; Cook, George Hammell, 1818-1889
    New Brunswick, N.J., A.L.S. 1p.,end. Acknowledging receipt of Society's publications.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], Jan. 6, 1887; 8-1/2x5-1/2; New York Public Library
    New York, A.L.S.:F[rederick] Saunders. 1p.,end. Enc. Thanks for publication. For enclosure, see letter from New York (City). Public library to APS, Jan.6, 1887.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], Jan. 6, 1887; 7x4-1/2; Wilson, Daniel, Sir, 1816-1892
    Toronto, A.L.S. 1p. Enc.wanting. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 6, 1887; 10x8; New York Public Library
    New York, Printed L. filled in in ms.S.:Robbins Little, superintendent. 1p. Thanks for publication. Enclosed originally in letter from New York(City). Public library to [Henry Phillips], Jan. 6, 1887.
  - Memorandum to secretaries of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips;]., Jan. 7, 1887; 12-1/2x8; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    A.D.S. 1p.and add.,end. Substance of the remarks he intended to make on the photographs of [E.] Muybridge.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 7, 1887; 9x6; Stowell, T. B. (Thomas Blanchard), 1846-1927
    Cortland, N.Y., A.L.S. 1p. Concerning the oversight of the Levytype co. in connection with his paper on the facial nerve in the cat.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 10, 1887; 11x8; Georgia Historical Society
    Savannah, A.L.S.:W[illia]m Harden,librarian. 1p., end. Concerning Society's publication. Refers to articles by [D.G.] Brinton.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 10, 1887; 8-1/2x5-1/2; New York Public Library
    New York, A.L.S.:F[rederick] Saunders. 1p., end. Thanks for offer of duplicate copy of Society's publication.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, Jan. 10, 1887; 3x5; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerning the time of the meeting.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 10, 1887; 8x5; Oliver, Charles A. (Charles Augustus), b. 1853
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. Thanks for publication. Asking for favor.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 11, 1887; 8x5; Murray, Joseph A. (Joseph Alexander), 1815-1889
    Carlisle, Pa., A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Jan. 12, 1887; 8x5; Allen, Harrison, 1841-1897
    A.L.S. 1p. Regrets that he cannot attend meeting of library committee.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, Jan. 13, 1887; 10x8; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Wash.,D.C., A.L.S. 4p.,end. ...Typed copy, end. Concerning rejection by publication committee of his paper on Lemurine reversion in human dentition.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 14, 1887; 10-1/2x8; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Enc. Sends him [E.D.] Cope's letter for presentation at the meeting on Friday night. For enclosure, see letter from Cope to Fraley, Jan.13, 1887.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 14, 1887; 3x5; New York Public Library
    New York, L.on postal card S.:Frederick Saunders. 1p.,end.,and add. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to Peter S. Du Ponceau, Jan. 15, 1887; 7 3/4" x 9 1/2"; Roux de Rochelle, 1762-1849
    Paris, Translation of L. (by P.S. Du Ponceau) 2p. and end. Acknowledges election to membership in the Society. Refers to Franklin. FILM54-67 FRAME77
    Not Found: 4/2011
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, Jan. 15, 1887; 10x8; Smithsonian Institution
    Wash.,D.C., T.L.S.:Spencer F.Baird,secretary. 1p. Enc.wanting. Concerning exchanges.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, Jan. 15, 1887; 8x5; Branner, John Casper, 1850-1922
    Bloomington, Ind., A.L.S. 1p. Asking for H.Allen's article on life form in art.
  - Letter to [Daniel G.] Brinton, Jan. 15, 1887; 8x5; Horsford, Eben Norton, 1818-1893
    Cambridge, [Mass.], A.L.S. 2p.,end. Concerning [J.] Heckewelder's work on Indian Linguistics. Refers to [D.] Zeisberger.
  - Letter to Henry M.Phillips [Henry Phillips], Jan. 16, 1887; 8x6; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Wash.,D.C., A.L.S. 1p.and end.by H[enry] P[hillips], and add. Concerning his paper on [Lemurine] reversion [in human dentition].
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 17, 1887; 8x5; American Academy of Arts and Sciences
    Boston, A.L.S.:Austin Holden. 1p.,end. Asking for middle name of H.C.Wood.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 17, 1887; 10x8; Royal Society of Tasmania
    Hobart, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.:Alex[ander] Morton. 1p. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to D[aniel] G.Brinton, Jan. 19, 1887; 10x8; Phillips, Henry, 1838-1895
    [Phila.], L.S.with initials. 1p.,end.by E[lla] M[orison],and end. Copy. Answering his questions[concerning E.D. Cope's paper on Lemurine reversion in human dentition].
  - Letter to Prof. E[dward] D.Cope, Jan. 19, 1887; 10x8; Phillips, Henry, 1838-1895
    [Phila.], L.S.with initials. 1p.,end.by E[lla] M[orison]. Copy. Mutilated. Concerning his paper on Lemurine reversion [in human dentition].
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, Jan. 19, 1887; 9-1/2x6; Brinton, Daniel Garrison, 1837-1899
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p.,end. Concerning [E.D.] Cope's paper on Lemurine [reversion in human] dentition.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 20, 1887; 8x5; Potts, William John, 1842-1895
    Camden, N.J., A.L.S. 1p. Concerning a donation for the Society's library. Mentions [J.F.] Garrison and [I.] Martindale.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 20, 1887; 5x3; Wood, H. C. (Horatio C.), 1841-1920
    [Phila.,] A.L.on postal card S.with initials. 1p. and add.,end. Concerning the initial in his name.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Jan. 22, 1887; 8x5; Biddle, Cadwalader, ca. 1837-1906
    A.L.S. 1p. Friendly letter. Congratulations [on his re-election as Librarian].
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Jan. 22, 1887; 9x5-1/2; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    [Phila.], A.L.in 3rd.P.S. 1p.,end. Order for W.C.Kerr's report on the geological survey of North Carolina.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 22, 1887; 7x4-1/2; Bigelow, John, 1817-1911
    New York, L.S. 3p. Asking for aid to obtain Congressional approval for the preparation of a descriptive catalogue of documents in European archives relating to American affairs, 1763-1783.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 23, 1887; 6x8; Claypole, E. W. (Edward Waller), 1835-1901
    Akron, T.L.S. 1p. Asking if he may present a paper on Variation at one of the Society's meetings.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, Jan. 25, 1887; 10x8; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Wash.,D.C., A.L.S. 2p.,end. Enc.wanting. ...Typed copy, with appended remarks. Asking him to appoint a committee to investigate a charge made against him at the last meeting of the Society.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 25, 1887; 11x8-1/2; Brooklyn Entomological Society
    Brooklyn, T.L.S.(in type):Richard F.Pearsall,librarian. 1p. Concerning publications and exchanges.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], Jan. 27, 1887; 8x5; Stevens, C. Ellis (Charles Ellis), 1853-1906
    Brooklyn, A.L.S. 1p. Asking about conditions of membership in Society.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], Jan. 28, 1887; 7x4-1/2; Lea, M. Carey (Mathew Carey), 1823-1897
    Phila., Printed L.filled in in ms.S.:M.Carey Lea, Henry C.Lea, Frances Lea. 1p. Announcing the death of Isaac Lea.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], Jan. 29, 1887; 3x5; Claypole, E. W. (Edward Waller), 1835-1901
    Akron, A.L.on postal card S. 1p.and add. Thanks for his vote. Concerning his paper [on Variation].
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 31, 1887; 10-1/2x8; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Enc.wanting. Concerning lists of attending members and committees, and suggestions for library committee. Refers to McCalla & Stavely.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 31, 1887; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Packard, A. S. (Alpheus Spring), 1839-1905
    Providence, A.L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting. Concerning his list of blind animals, which [E.D.] Cope was to present for publication.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan.?, 1887; 8x5; American Academy of Arts and Sciences
    Boston, []. A.L.S.:Austin Holden. 1p. Enc.wanting. Thanks for information about [H.C.] Wood's name. Concerning publications.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 1, 1887; 9x5-1/2; M’Calla & Stavely
    Phila., L. 1p. Enc.wanting. Asking for approval of the enclosed statement concerning printing notices.
  - Letter to [J.Peter] Lesley, Feb. 2, 1887; 10x8; Phillips, Henry, 1838-1895
    T.L.S. 1p. Asking how Franklin manuscripts, Lee manuscripts and the rough draft of the Declaration came into Society's possession. On same sheet is letter from J.P.Lesley to [Henry Phillips], [Feb.2, 1887]. FILM54-66 FRAME226
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 2, 1887; 8-1/2x5-1/2; College of Physicians of Philadelphia
    Phila., A.L.S.:Isaac Norris, secretary. 1p.,end. Thanks for loan of portraits at the late centennial celebration of the college.
  - Letter to [Henry Phillips;], Feb. 2, 1887; 10x8; Lesley, J. P. (J. Peter), 1819-1903
    A.L.S. 1p. Concerning [Franklin manuscripts, Lee manuscripts and the rough draft of the Declaration]. Refers to G.Ord, [C.] Trego, and T.Jefferson. On same sheet as letter from H.Phillips to [J.P.] Lesley, Feb.2, 1887. FILM 199 FRAME 720 FILM54-66 FRAME226
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, Feb. 3, 1887; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Enc.wanting. Sends list of the standing committees for 1887. Mentioned are [J.] Baker, [C.] Cresson, [F.] Jordan, [E.] Barber, and [H.] Allen.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 7, 1887; 11x8-1/2; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p.,end. Enc.wanting Returns book. Concerning paper by D.G. Brinton.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 8, 1887; 7-1/2x5; Booth, James Curtis, 1810-1888
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Enc.wanting. Sends documents soliciting Congressional approval of a descriptive catalogue of documents in European archives relating to American affairs, 1763-1783, and asks Society to act on them.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 9, 1887; 8x5; Houston, Edwin J. (Edwin James), 1847-1914
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p.,end. Concerning meeting of library committee.
  - Letter to Council of the American philosophical society, Feb. 9, 1887; 12-1/2x8; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Wash.,D.C., A.L.S. 3p.,end.,and end. ...Typed copy, with appended remarks referring to [E.] Kendall, [P.] Frazer and [W.] McKean. Concerning his paper [on Lemurine reversion in human dentition]. Refers to G.H. Horn,D.G.Brinton and H.Phillips.
  - Letter to [Henry] P[hillips], Feb. 9, 1887; 9x5-1/2; Brinton, Daniel Garrison, 1837-1899
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p.,end. Enc.wanting. He cannot vote for printing [S.N.Clevenger's] paper on Comets.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], Feb. 10, 1887; 3x5; University of Illinois (Urbana-Champaign campus)
    Champaign, A.L.on postal card S.:J.D.Crawford,librarian. 1p.and add. Concerning publication.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 11, 1887; 3x5; Stokes, Alfred C.
    Trenton, A.L.on postal card S. 1p.and add.,end. Concerning the plate of illustrations for his paper. Refers to McCalla & Stavely
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 11, 1887[1888]; 3x5; Johns Hopkins University. Peabody Institute
    Baltimore, A.L.on postal card S.:N[athaniel] H.Morison,provost. 1p.and add. Concerning publications.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Feb. 12, 1887; 7x4-1/2; Snyder, Monroe Benjamin, 1848-1932
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 2p.,end. Concerning S.Clevenger's paper on Comets
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 14, 1887; 9x5-1/2; M’Calla & Stavely
    Phila., L. 1p.and end. Concerning [E.D.] Cope's paper on Lemurine reversion [in human dentition].
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 14, 1887; 8x5; McKean, W. V. (William Vincent), 1820-1902
    Phila., L.S. 2p. Concerning the error in his address on the Society's card notices of meetings.
  - Letter to J. P. Lesley, Feb. 17, 1886; Herrick, C. L. (Clarence Luther), 1858-1903
    A.L.S. 1p.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], Feb. 18, 1887; 3x5; Whitman, Francis L.
    Portland, Ore., A.L.on postal card S. 1p.and add.,end. Asking for information about Society.
  - Memorandum:, Feb. 18, 1887; 8x5; American Philosophical Society
    in which the undersigned desire to correct an error in the vote on the motion to take from the Council the further consideration of the matter concerning Prof.[E.D.] Cope; Feb. 18, 1887. D.S.:George A.Koenig, Horace Jayne, Charles S.Dolley, Persifor Frazer, E.Y.McCauley, Harrison Allen, and Daniel R. Goodwin. 1p.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Feb. 23, 1887; 8x5; Hale, Edward Everett, 1822-1909
    Boston, A.L.S. 2p.,end. Enc.wanting. Concerning a letter for [P. Garrett], who is Preparing an obituary of [P.] Chase.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, Feb. 23, 1887; 10x8; Schoneman, Charles
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Asking about the word "monistic" which he found in a review of the writings of [Charles ?] Darwin and others.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 23, 1887; 11x8; Chesney, C. S.
    Wash.,D.C. A.L.S. 1p.,end. Concerning address of William Ludlow.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 23, 1887; 11x9; Deutsche Physikalische Gesellschaft
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.:O[tto R.] Lummer. 1p.,end. In German. Concerning publications.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 23, 1887; 8x5; Potts, William John, 1842-1895
    Camden, A.L.S. 1p. Asking for package of books.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, Feb. 24, 1887; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Asking for copy of [P.] Frazer's resolution discharging committee in the matter [E.D.] Cope's communications.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 24, 1887; 8x5; Benjamin, Marcus, 1857-1932
    New York, A.L.S. 2p. Enc.wanting. Concerning Clark, J[ohn] I[nnis], and Robert Hare. Refers to [F.] Fraley. Asking about W.Gabb.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 26, 1887; 3x5; Stokes, Alfred C.
    Trenton, N.J., A.L.on postal card S. 1p.,end.,and add. Concerning the plates to accompany his paper.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 26, 1887; 9x5-/2; Ruschenberger, W. S. W. (William Samuel Waithman), 1807-1895
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p.,end. Asking correction in the Proceedings for Feb.18, regarding vote on [P.] Frazer's resolution.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, Feb. 27, 1887; 7x4-1/2; Crane, Thomas Frederick, 1844-1927
    Ithaca, A.L.S. 3p. Will be unable to give Society the article he promised.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, Feb. 28, 1887; 8x5; "Baboika"
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Enc.wanting. Submits paper on a method of determining the moon's mass, for the Magellanic premium.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 1, 1887; 10-1/2x8; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 2p.and end. Concerning the error in the vote on [P.] Frazer's motion. Refers to [E.D.] Cope, and [W.] Ruschenberger.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], March 3, 1887; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Casey, Thos. L. (Thomas Lincoln), 1857-1925
    San Francisco, A.L.S. 1p.,end. Asking for [G.H.] Horn's article on Tenebrionidae.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 4, 1887; 12-1/2x8; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    A.L.S. 1p.,end. ...Typed copy, end. Asking committee of inquiry relative to his paper on Lemurine reversion in human dentition. Refers to G.H.Horn. Enclosed originally in letter from P. Frazer to F.Fraley, March 4, 1887.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, March 4, 1887; 10-1/2x8-1/2; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Enc. Sends E.D.Cope's letter. Asking him to appoint committee of inquiry. For enclosure, see letter from Cope to APS, [March, 4, 1887].
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, March 4, 1887; 11x8-1/2; Stevenson, John J. (John James), 1841-1924
    New York, T.L.S. 1p.and end. Asking why [G.] Meneghini failed of election to membership in the Society. Mentions [J.P.] Lesley and [G.] Capellini.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 5, 1887; 10-1/2x8; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p.,end. Mutilated. Appoints the following members to be the committee to make the investigation requested by E.D. Cope:W. Ingham, J. Leidy, D. Agnew, C. Biddle, A. Smith, H. Furness and W. Tatham.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 8, 1887; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    A.L.S. 1p. Concerning the sale of the French Rentes [Michaux legacy].
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, March 8, 1887; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Stevenson, John J. (John James), 1841-1924
    New York, A.L.S. 1p. Enc.wanting. Returns letter. Asking when his paper will be read.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 9, 1887; 10-1/2x8; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Concerning sale and transfer of [French] Rentes [Michaux legacy].
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, March 10, 1887; 11x8-1/2; Franklin Institute (Philadelphia, Pa.)
    Phila., L.S.:W[illia]m H.Wahl,secretary. 1p. Enc.wanting. Invites members of Society to a discussion on Japanese archaeology by T.Baba.
  - Letter to [Frederick] Fraley, March 10, 1887; 8x5; Furness, Horace Howard, 1833-1912
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 3p. Declines to serve on the committee to investigate certain charges preferred by [E.D.] Cope in connection with his paper on Lemurine reversion [in human dentition].
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, March 11, 1887; 10x7-1/2; Winnipeg. Board of trade
    Winnipeg, L.S.:Char[les] N.Bell,secretary. 1p. Concerning publications.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 14, 1887; 7x4-1/2; Billings, John S. (John Shaw), 1838-1913
    Wash.,D.C., L.S. 1p. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to H.M.Phillips [Henry Phillips], March 14, 1887; 7-1/2x8; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p.and add. Mutilated. Concerning the notice on a card of the matter between himself and the publication committee.
  - Memorandum pertaining to the meeting of the committee appointed to consider the charges brought by [E.D.] Cope in connection with the rejection of his paper on Lemurine reversion [in human dentition], March 14, 1887; 8x8; Ingham, William A. (William Armstrong), 1827-1913
    D.S. 1p.and end.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 14, 1887; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Koninklijk Zoölogisch Genootschap Natura Artis Magistra, te Amsterdam
    Amsterdam, Printed L.on postal card filled in in ms.S.:G.F.Westerman,director. 1p.,end.,and add. Partly in Dutch. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 14, 1887; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Smith, Aubrey H., ca. 1813-1891
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Acknowledges appointment to committee to investigate charges preferred by [E.D.] Cope in connection with his paper on Lemurine reversion [in human dentition].
  - Letter to W[illiam] A.Ingham, March 15, 1887; 7x4-1/2; Agnew, D. Hayes (David Hayes), 1818-1892
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Declines to serve on committee in regard to [E.D.] Cope's case.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 17, 1887; 10x8; Breuker & Kessler, co.
    Phila., L. 1p.and add. Printing matter.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 17, 1887; 8x7; Casey, Thos. L. (Thomas Lincoln), 1857-1925
    San Francisco, A.L.S. 1p.and end. Enc.wanting. Sends money for [G.H.] Horn's article on Tenebrionidae.
  - Letter to W[illiam] A.Ingham, March 17, 1887; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Smith, Aubrey H., ca. 1813-1891
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Will be unable to meet the committee in re [E.D.] Cope.
  - Letter to W[illiam] A.Ingham, March 18, 1887; 7x4-1/2; Agnew, D. Hayes (David Hayes), 1818-1892
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Will be unable to attend meeting of the committee.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 19, 1887; 8x5; Barnwell, James G.
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerning John Vaughan.
  - Letter to [Persifor] Frazer, March 21, 1887; 3x5; D'Auria, Luigi
    Phila., A.L.on postal card S. 2p. Asking him to inform [F.Fraley] that he wishes to withdraw his paper on the moon's mass which he submitted for the Magellanic premium. Enclosed originally in letter from P. Frazer to F.Fraley, March 22, 1887.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, March 22, 1887; 9x5-1/2; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Enc. Sends [L.] d'Auria's note. Concerning the award for the Magellanic premium. For enclosure, see letter from L.d'Auria to [p.] Frazer, March 21, 1887.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 22, 1887; 8x5; Library Company of Philadelphia
    Phila., A.L.S.:James G.Barnwell,librarian. 2p. Thanks for favor. Refers to his predecessors [L.P.and J.J.Smith].
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 23, 1887; 3x5; Chapman, Henry C. (Henry Cadwalader), 1845-1909
    [Phila.,]. A.L.on postal card S. 1p.,end.,and add. Asking for publication.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 23, 1887; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    Surrey, [Eng.], A.L.S.in 3rd.P. 1p. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], March 24, 1887; 3x5; "Baboika"
    Phila., A.L.on postal card S. 2p. Wishes to withdraw memoir on the moon's mass which he submitted for the Magellanic premium.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 24, 1887; 3x5; Stevenson, John J. (John James), 1841-1924
    New York, A.L.on postal card S. 1p.and add. Concerning letter from [J.P.] Lesley.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 25, 1887; 8x10-1/2; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Enc.wanting. Concerning the Magellanic premium, and the appointment of J.P. Lesley to represent the Society at Columbia College.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 27, 1887; 3x5; Genth, F. A. (Frederick Augustus), 1820-1893
    [Phila.], A.L.on postal card S. 1p.and add.,end. Concerning publications. Asking about his paper.
  - Letter to secretaries of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], March 28, 1887; 11x8-1/2; Claypole, E. W. (Edward Waller), 1835-1901
    Akron, Typed L.S. 1p. Enc.wanting. Sends the paper he promised.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 2, 1887; 3x5; Genth, F. A. (Frederick Augustus), 1820-1893
    [Phila.], A.L.on postal card S. 1p.and add.,end. Thanks for publication. Asking about woodcuts.
  - Letter to J.L. Phillips [Henry Phillips], April 2, 1887; 7x4-1/2; Napier, John T., ca. 1858-1887
    Scotland, A.L.S. 1p.,end. Enc.wanting. Sends subscription fee, and new address.
  - Letter to President of A.P.S.[Frederick Fraley], April 3, 1887; 9x6; Rittenhouse, Jessie B. (Jessie Belle), 1869-1948
    Buffalo, A.L.S. 2p.,end. Asking about Memoirs of David Rittenhouse, by T.[sic] Barton. Refers to B. Franklin. FILM54-66 FRAME229
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 4, 1887; 10-1/2x8; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p.,end. Concerning the representative to Columbia College, and the committee on membership. Refers to Kendall, [G.F.] Barker, Brinton, Frazer, Thomson, Goodwin, and Ingham.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 4, 1887; 8x5-1/2; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    A.L.S. 1p. Enc.wanting. Encloses written version of the verbal remarks that he made on [G.F.] Barker's paper.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 6, 1887; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Mooney, James, 1861-1921
    Wash.,D.C., A.L.S. 1p.,end. Asking if Society will publish his paper on Medical mythology of Ireland. Refers to A.S.Catschet.